[nervous panting]
[panicked grunting]
[tense music plays]
-[knocking at door]
-[gasps]
Good morning, miss.
[yawns]
Rose.
Has my mother yet awakened?
I did not overindulge.
Truly, it was just a poor night of sleep.
I shall fetch a glass
of raw eggs and garlic, ma'am.
Should be just the thing.
[Violet sighs]
Are you feeling better, dearest?
Perhaps I, too, caught whatever it was
that sent you home early from the party.
I have a terrible headache, indeed.
What is it?
[exhales sharply]
I am engaged.
Oh! [chuckles]
Well, that is wonderful news.
So, you will be a princess.
-No.
-No?
No, I will not.
Mama, I am engaged to the duke.
The duke asked for my hand,
and I accepted.
[gasps]
You do not seem pleased.
Whatever is wrong?
Oh no. No-- Nothing is wrong.
It simply happened so quickly.
I've not had a moment to take it in.
But I am overjoyed, Mama, truly.
Of course you are.
You are to be a duchess!
Oh, darling! [laughs]
I knew there was something between you…
ruse or not!
Well, tell me. Tell me everything!
How do you feel?
-So in love.
-[Violet laughs]
I'm unsure how I can be expected
to wait an entire month to marry.
Could we not obtain a special license
to marry this week?
I do not wish to lie to you…
-But the duke and I--
-You do not need to tell me anything.
Whatever happened
between the two of you,
it is all right. [chuckles]
I know good society
makes quite a fuss about such things…
but when it comes to love,
such things happen
more frequently than one might expect.
Even your father and I, we had trouble
controlling our passions as well.
[Wilson] Your drink, ma'am.
Will not be necessary, Wilson.
I am feeling much improved.
We have a wedding to plan in three days.
My darling girl,
you are getting what you always wanted.
You are marrying for love.
[theme music plays]
[Violet chuckles lightly]
[Lady Whistledown]
<span style="style2">One may say modesty is a virtue,
yet this author
is hardly a virtuous woman.
It is therefore my great pleasure
to announce the news others questioned,
but I never doubted.
It will be
the grandest wedding of the year.
Tulips enough to fill the great room
and the finest silks.
Only the best
for Miss Bridgerton and my nephew.
The latest Whistledown?
How does she report my triumph?
[moans nervously]
[Lady Whistledown] <span style="style2">The diamond
<span style="style2">of the season has made her match,
officially betrothed
to the Duke of Hastings.
Has something happened?
The bride, undoubtedly,
is giddy with anticipation
over the impending nuptials…
I shall need fittings for the dress
and my trousseau.
-[Rose grunts]
-And, oh…
-I am forgetting something, surely.
-I shall take care of everything.
Just think, you shall be the duchess
by Saturday. [chuckles]
…an event that will apparently take place
sooner rather than later.
[horses neighing]
Of course, there are only two reasons
to procure a special license
and race to the altar:
true love,
or concealing a scandal.
How does it feel, sister, to be in love?
Imagine leaping off a cliff
and shattering on the ground.
A fair analogy?
I am afraid I cannot find
the words, dear Hyacinth.
Though, Eloise, I believe
you will know what love feels like
soon enough next season.
You think I am
to follow in your footsteps?
Can there be a more dreadful fate?
You do know that I am setting
the standard for your future matches, yes?
You should be grateful.
The only thing I am grateful for
is that I am not you, nor will I ever be.
Miss Daphne, His Royal Highness
Prince Friedrich is here for you.
-I am sorry.
-You have nothing to be sorry for.
No… No promises were made.
Although,
I thought we shared an understanding
with our discussions of the future.
But, uh…
the fault is mine for misreading
your polite attentions as something more.
No. You did not misread me.
Then why…
This engagement is
of your own free will, is it not?
-[Daphne chuckles]
-If the duke is forcing your hand--
Forcing me?
My goodness!
If anything, I am the one forcing him.
What I mean to say
is that love is surely
the greatest force of all.
Once the duke and I realized
we were completely enamored
with each other,
nothing could stand between us.
Not even, I'm sorry to say,
the attentions of a good
and kind man such as yourself.
Then I can only wish you a lifetime
of contentment with your new husband.
It was a pleasure to know you,
Miss Bridgerton.
[door creaking]
Hyacinth!
I could not help it, sister.
Though, I must say,
I certainly hope the duke's proposal
was at least half as romantic as that.
-Did we not say ten o'clock?
-[Daphne grunts lightly]
We did.
There he is.
Well, do not make haste on our account.
A most heartfelt congratulations,
Your Grace.
I look forward
to counting you as part of our family.
-As do I.
-[Violet chuckles]
Did you bring the bar with you, boy?
Perhaps we should promenade?
[Simon clears throat]
[sniffs]
-[Daphne] Have you--
-[Simon] I should--
[Simon grunts]
[chuckles] I was…
I was going to ask if you had tried
drinking raw eggs and garlic.
I hear it works wonders to rid yourself
of the lingering effects of…
-What were you going to say?
-What?
Before, you started to say something.
Oh, I-- I do not recall.
Simon, look at me.
Well, if it isn't the most
talked-about couple in the ton.
Such a perfect-looking pair.
Indeed. The two of you
will make a fine family, I am sure of it.
Thank you.
-We are so happy.
-Very much so.
[Lord Wetherby] Hmm.
I remember that feeling,
the nerves of new love.
-Or something like it.
-[Violet chuckles]
-Madame Delacroix, good day. May I--
-She is not here.
I only beg a moment of her time.
She does not owe me her time, I know that.
She does not owe me anything.
But I wish to provide for her regardless,
as I promised.
She will be taken care of.
-Will you tell her?
-You are too late. Siena's gone.
Gone?
You mean, she's left town?
Indeed.
As it transpires, my lord,
she does not need your money,
nor anything else from you,
for that matter.
-Tell me where she is?
-Leave the young lady alone.
Have you not done enough?
[clears throat]
It seems Mrs. Varley had some trouble
at the modiste this morning.
Madame Delacroix is refusing
to give her any of the dresses
until the last few months' bills are paid.
The young ladies have plenty of dresses.
Perhaps it is possible
for them to wear them all again.
And perhaps it is possible for you
to do without your tobacco as well!
Mr. Colin Bridgerton for Miss Thompson.
Oh, Mr. Bridgerton, these are beautiful.
I applaud you, Miss Thompson.
I bring you flowers on each of my visits,
and yet you react
with admirable surprise every time.
I shall need
to bring you something unexpected.
-A bushel of tomatoes, perhaps.
-Oh! [laughs]
Marina hates tomatoes.
That is untrue.
I love tomatoes.
Colin, you know where I have heard
you can get excellent tomatoes?
Greece.
Perhaps you could
bring back a tomato plant
for Miss Thompson as a souvenir
when you return
from your travels this year.
I am uncertain of my travels
at the moment, Pen.
-But you were so keen to travel.
-It is true.
But, were I to go,
there may be things in London
I should miss even more
than seeing the world.
-Some tea, Mr. Bridgerton?
-That would be lovely.
Mama?
-Do you think this is wise?
-Whatever do you mean?
Colin is young,
years from seriously thinking
about marriage.
I would hate to think
Marina is simply wasting her time,
time she simply does not have, of course.
That is all.
[kitchen staff clamoring]
Your mistress will not know
the household staff
at the duke's country home,
so it will be your business
to attend to her needs
and ease her arrival.
Her happiness is your greatest concern.
Oh no!
No, no, no!
The icing must be as white as lilies.
This is a proper family.
A shipment of fine sugar went down at sea.
There is no more in London,
for love nor money.
Does Miss Daphne wish
for roses or lilacs for the ceremony?
Uh…
Does your mistress wish the cake
to be soaked in rum or brandy?
Will it be tongue
or ham with eggs for the reception?
I am not sure. I shall ask.
Rose, you are
the future duchess's lady's maid.
You must know these things.
[Genevieve] Your wedding gown
is a long way from being finished,
Miss Bridgerton.
I promise you will not be disappointed.
She will need a new pelisse too,
and then the more intimate items.
Four nightdresses, perhaps? Or five?
What could I possibly need
with five new nightdresses?
They are not for you, <span style="style2">ma chère,
but for your <span style="style2">amoureux.
What else do you think a honeymoon is for?
It will be a most special time, dear.
[shop door closes]
Yes, five. Five nightdresses
will do nicely. [chuckles]
Daphne!
How lovely to see you.
Oh, I do hope
your wedding dress will be ready in time.
Madam Delacroix must be working so fast.
Mama, might you spare me a moment?
I must have Cressida's opinion
on some fabric.
Her taste is impeccable.
Of course, dear.
I am to have a new pelisse
for my honeymoon.
What about this color?
Trimmed with fur, perhaps.
Fur, at this time of year?
Well, I suppose it depends
on how much time
you and the duke spend outdoors.
But you are fond
of a midnight garden stroll, I believe.
I do not know what you mean.
I am almost certain I saw the two of you
in the gardens at the Trowbridge ball.
No chaperone in sight.
How strange.
I do not recall leaving the ballroom.
[Cressida] Hmm.
Though I dare say
it would have been difficult
to see the gardens
with any real clarity at night,
unless you were actually
out in them yourself.
My view of the garden was perfectly clear
from the safety of the terrace, Daphne.
You dallied with the prince
purely to rouse the duke's jealousy,
and then you lured him into those gardens
to trap him into marriage.
I never would have imagined
that a Bridgerton
would ever come to know such shame.
You should consider
your words more carefully, Cressida.
In a matter of days, I am to be a duchess,
and you shall be just as you are now,
unmarried and untitled.
So you can either be
a duchess's friend or her enemy.
It is entirely up to you.
[scoffs]
First, let us see if you actually manage
to drag him down that aisle at all.
I would imagine
a man like the duke does not take kindly
to being forced into anything.
[tense music plays]
[nervous breathing]
["Beethoven's 5th Symphony" plays]
[Prince Friedrich]
I bid you farewell, <span style="style2">Tante.
I shall be returning
to Prussia this afternoon.
Am I to believe you truly long
for sweet pickles and sauerkraut?
Fight for the girl!
Hastings is merely a duke.
You are a prince.
I have no interest in brandishing my title
before the young lady, nor do I need to.
I am happy for them.
Everyone is happy for them.
You have read
of what your dear Whistledown writes.
What do you want?
-It is the king, Your Majesty.
-Dead?
Lucid.
[exasperated sigh]
Auf Wiedersehen, <span style="style1">if you must go.
While you may be content to accept defeat…
it is certainly not how I approach things.
[church bells ringing]
[Simon] Apologies for my tardiness.
Not at all.
The archbishop is yet to arrive.
[church bells continue]
-We should discuss Daphne's dowry.
-There is nothing to discuss.
-I will not accept one.
-I beg your pardon?
I need not be paid to marry Daphne.
It is an insulting custom in my judgment.
You may place the money in trust for her,
but you need not harbor any doubts
of my intention to support your sister.
Her well-being is my responsibility now.
I take that duty
with the utmost seriousness.
I must apologize for, uh…
well…
-Shooting at me?
-Indeed.
[Simon chuckles lightly]
I would have thought you dishonorable
had you not.
Besides,
you have always been a terrible shot.
You'd have stood
a greater chance of wounding me
if you had simply fired
straight up in the air.
[chuckles] Your Grace.
May I express my gratitude
for your granting of this special license?
Perhaps, my lord, you should not.
Denied?
What on earth for?
The archbishop of Canterbury
did not think he owed me an explanation.
If we are to wait weeks for this wedding,
it gives Cressida Cowper,
not to mention Whistledown
and anyone else,
far too much time to uncover
the truth of what happened in that garden.
Simon--
Lady Danbury.
Welcome!
Welcome! Is everyone as famished as I?
[chuckles]
Now, this is far too grim a mood
for the celebration I was counting on.
-What on earth is the matter?
-Anthony?
We have been denied our request
for a special license.
-What?
-The archbishop did not see a need.
[Violet inhales sharply]
It is not the archbishop.
It is the queen.
Perhaps she has taken
your rejection of her nephew to heart,
or perhaps she is simply bored.
Either way, it does not bode well
for your daughter's social future,
nor any of the Bridgertons,
for that matter.
Surely we must be able to do something?
Give her what she wants.
Attention.
Appear before her yourselves
and make a personal appeal.
But she will not respond to begging,
and she can sniff out even
the faintest whiff of insincerity,
so do not lay it on thick.
Tell her you are in love,
plain and simple and true.
You can do that, can you not?
Good.
-Now, where is the dinner I was promised?
-[Violet chuckles]
[muffled revelry]
-Bridgerton! I am so glad you came.
-I dare not miss it.
Please, come in.
Make yourself at home.
I would show you around,
but host duty calls.
[Benedict chuckles]
[guests clamoring]
[Genevieve] What are you doing here?
Apologies. Have we met?
We do not need to have met.
You are a Bridgerton, yes?
I see my reputation precedes me.
[ironic chuckle] Not exactly a virtue.
Anything that gets me your attention
is a good thing, I rather think.
You should go,
home to your brother, perhaps.
[chuckling scoff]
But I'm receiving
far too warm a welcome here.
[clamoring continues]
[Benedict panting]
[both grunting, moaning]
[Genevieve whispering] Bridgerton.
[all panting]
[raucous clamoring]
[Simon singing indistinctly]
[Will interrupts]
Is that how the tune goes?
It's a bloody love song, I think.
Happy to hear you're embracing the genre.
Where is my drink?
Did they kick you out?
My God, they kicked you out--
Will marrying the girl truly be so bad?
I know you care for her.
Feelings are irrelevant.
Indeed, they're responsible for this mess.
I let them get the better of me.
Now she has to fight
for a wedding she doesn't even want.
You think someone
wrote a love song about that?
Hey, tell him
to play the one about the trapped wife!
All right, friend,
time to get you out of here.
[door opens]
[door closes]
[Lady Featherington]
I've invited Lord Rutledge
to dine with us Saturday.
You have until then to muster
appropriate enthusiasm for his proposal.
I could have until Judgment Day
and still not manage a smile
for that wretched fate.
[Lady Featherington]
Despite all obstacles,
I have managed to find a man
who will overlook
your current circumstance
and offer you some security.
You should be lavishing me with gratitude,
and yet you merely sit here and sulk.
Hmm.
Is this about Mr. Bridgerton?
He likes me.
He'll propose to me, I am sure of it.
That boy is barely out of leading strings.
He has two older brothers
still running from the yoke.
You are
to cut Colin Bridgerton immediately,
or I will lock you in this room
till the day
Lord Rutledge makes you his wife.
Lady Featherington, wait.
You are right. You have been kind to me.
And I should like
to repay you for that kindness.
If I were to marry Mr. Bridgerton,
you would be connected to what I gather
is a very powerful family, indeed.
Think what that could do for your girls.
Give me until Saturday.
If I have not secured a proposal
from Mr. Bridgerton by then,
I shall accept Lord Rutledge
with a smile on my face.
My girl, you are
six months away from motherhood,
seven if you're lucky.
And even if a miracle were to occur,
and Colin Bridgerton proposed tomorrow,
the wedding wouldn't be for weeks.
That is only assuming
we wait until the wedding night
to consummate the union.
You will seduce him?
[Marina] I will do what I must.
[Lady Featherington] Very well.
You have until Saturday.
My king.
No need for the formality, Lottie.
Sit with me.
How is little George?
Well, he is not so little anymore.
Grows plumper by the day, in fact.
I am quite sure he does. [chuckles]
Your subjects miss you, my dear.
I miss you.
I'm right here, Lottie.
I was just remembering
the bluebells in the cottage garden.
-Ah.
-Do you recall when you first saw them?
You said it was
as if we were walking in the clouds.
[chuckles] You had just filled the paddock
with kangaroos, of all things.
-Yes. [laughs]
-Dreadful creatures.
-How are the gardens coming along?
-Oh, they are in full bloom.
After your meal, perhaps we could
take a walk, like we used to do.
And how is dear Emily?
Can you bring her to me?
George…
Amelia was ill…
several years ago.
She came to my room but a fortnight ago.
Did you not see her?
She is gone, George.
What did you…?
Have you done something?
What have you done?
What has this woman done to my child?
George…
No! What have you done?
-What have you done?
-[servant] Your Majesty…
No, you come back here!
She has killed my child!
You bitch!
[exhales]
[sighs deeply]
[sighs]
-[Rose] Miss?
-[Daphne gasps]
Rose.
-Is everything all right?
-I cannot sleep.
It is quite late
for you to be up, too, is it not?
There is much to be done.
If you're nervous about the wedding,
you need not worry.
I assure you,
I am managing everything.
-I will be ready.
-I know you will.
You are not who I worry about.
The duke.
-Has he asked to beg off, miss?
-No.
But he may wish to.
Every man entertains doubt
before the day, I rather think,
but it does not signify.
He will be a good husband to you.
A good father as well.
[quivering inhale]
Miss?
He cannot have children.
I shall not pretend to understand
the extent of his physical impediment,
but I imagine it is a source
of great pain for the duke, indeed.
I have an aunt.
She lives in Greenwich with her husband.
They have been married for ten years now
and never blessed with children,
but they still are to each other
as husband and wife.
-Theirs is a happy union.
-Because they love each other.
At least your aunt has that.
I shall not keep you, Rose.
You must have a hundred things to do.
Of course, miss. Good night.
[sighs]
You smell bad.
[Alice] Nicky! Stop pestering him.
[baby coos]
[Simon grunts, sniffs]
Why must everything be so bright?
It is called "day" for a reason.
Charcoal and oil will soak up
everything in your gut.
Eat.
If I am, in fact, to marry…
I would like
the both of you to be present.
"If"? He seems to believe
there is a way out of this.
[chuckles] We would be honored to attend.
Good.
[Alice] Have you told the duke
about your exhibition series business?
Alice…
Will is seeking more investors
for a series of matches.
Perhaps, Your Grace,
you and your future brother-in-law
might be interested in investing?
The viscount certainly owes you something
after shooting at you.
-Alice!
-What?
I am sure His Grace understands
the basic tenets of marriage,
or at least he will.
Everything you know, I know.
And everything I know…
Well, you eventually catch up.
-[Simon chuckles]
-Pay her no mind.
That's what I do. [chuckles]
[Will, Alice laughing]
-Ah!
-Right, dears, come on. Out you go.
[dogs panting]
[dog barks softly]
As low as you can go, Lady Danbury?
With these knees, yes, Your Majesty.
Very well.
Let your young people come forward.
I have heard a rumor
that the special license
you seek to marry has been denied.
I am not quite sure
what you believe <span style="style2">I am to do about it.
Well, plead your case.
Your Majesty, I assure you
nothing untoward has occurred.
It is only that
we love each other so very much.
[sighs]
While I was deeply flattered
by the attention
of your nephew, the prince,
I…
I simply could not ignore
my long-standing affection for the duke.
You see, Your Majesty,
it was love at first sight.
It was not, Your Majesty.
The young lady flatters me,
but it was not love at first sight
for either of us.
There was attraction,
certainly, at least on my part.
But Miss Bridgerton thought me
presumptuous, arrogant, insincere.
All fair, really.
And I thought her a prim young lady
barely out of leading strings.
Not to mention
the sister of my best friend,
and so romance was entirely
out of the question for both of us.
But in so removing it,
we found something far greater.
We found friendship.
You see, Miss Bridgerton and I have been
fooling all of Mayfair for some time.
We have fooled them
into thinking we are courting…
when really, all along,
we simply enjoyed
each other's company so much
we could not stay away from one another.
I have never been a man
that much enjoyed flirting, or chatting,
or, indeed, talking at all.
But with Daphne…
Miss Bridgerton…
conversation has always been easy.
Her laughter brings me joy.
To meet a beautiful woman is one thing,
but to meet your best friend
in the most beautiful of women
is something entirely apart.
And it is with my sincerest apologies,
I must say it took the prince coming along
for me to realize I did not want
Miss Bridgerton to only be my friend.
I wanted her to be my wife.
I want her to be my wife.
And so I plead with you…
not to make us wait.
Simon…
[Queen Charlotte] You are wise…
or perhaps unusually lucky
to understand friendship
to be the best possible foundation
a marriage can have.
Even if that foundation should crumble
as quickly as it was built.
I shall like to offer you the choice,
Miss Bridgerton.
Do you wish to marry this man?
[attendees whispering]
[door opens]
Dearly beloved,
we are gathered to join together
this man and this woman in holy matrimony.
It is said that marriage hath in it
less of beauty
but more of safety than the single life.
[dramatic choral music plays]
…in the name of the Father,
of the Son, and of the Holy Ghost. Amen.
I now pronounce you man and wife.
[upbeat classical violin music plays]
[guests conversing]
[woman 1] It was such a beautiful wedding.
Thank you for having us.
[woman 2] Your Grace.
I suppose congratulations are in order.
[chuckles]
We being friends, after all.
I do hope you will remember my kindness
in keeping secrets and repay me someday.
Enjoy your triumph, Your Grace.
What about him?
He seems…
pleasant.
[gasps]
Or him.
Kind eyes.
A fine enough husband, I think.
Pen, I neither know nor have time
for any of these men.
Now, where is Colin?
You can choose anyone but him.
He is my friend, Marina.
I have known him forever.
And I do not want him to be tricked
and deceived into a lifelong commitment.
You must not do this to a good man.
Well, should I perhaps
entrap a bad man, then?
Perhaps you would find it acceptable
for me to live my life with a man
who treats me like a mere beast?
-No, I only mean--
-What am I to do, Penelope?
I will be a good wife to Colin,
and he a good husband and father…
however young
and well-liked by you he may be.
Miss Thompson,
you will be delighted to know
that Lord Rutledge is no longer available.
He is engaged as of this morning.
That is…
How terrible.
Best hope that whatever you have planned
for Mr. Bridgerton actually works.
It is your last hope.
[inaudible conversation]
Oh! [Penelope gasps]
-I should--
-As should I.
I am beginning to feel a bit faint.
Perhaps you know
of a more private place
where I might catch my breath?
Certainly, Miss Thompson. Please.
[Marina] Hmm.
-[guests clamoring]
-This is much more comfortable. Thank you.
Though it is still quite loud.
Oh, of course.
[Colin breathes deeply]
-We should not be alone in here.
-No, we should not.
Hmm.
I can hardly believe I am saying this,
but we cannot go further.
You are a lady,
and I must maintain your honor and mine,
no matter how… tempting otherwise.
-Have I offended you?
-No. [chuckles]
You are right.
I am a lady.
I am unmarried.
And you…
You are…
a gentleman.
Then marry me.
I know we have only known each other
a short while, but…
Well, would you want to marry me,
Miss Thompson?
I would be delighted to marry you!
-What are we waiting for?
-My thoughts exactly.
We will marry by the end of the season.
-It's a rather long engagement.
-Or simply romantic.
You deserve a grand wedding.
Our families will need time to plan.
-It will be wonderful, I promise you.
-[chuckles]
But let us not say anything now.
It is my sister's day.
Of course.
[chuckles]
[chuckles softly]
Your Majesty.
I must say, I am honored
and most grateful for your presence.
And I must say,
I hope you made the right choice.
Well, either way,
I suppose you will enjoy
your wedding night, at the very least.
Yes, you certainly enjoy
spreading secrets, do you not?
Dear child, have you lost your wits?
Everyone enjoys secrets.
Otherwise, why would
Lady Whistledown's paper be so successful?
I am flattered by your accusation,
but it is simply not true.
Though, when you unmask the writer,
do let me know.
You believe Whistledown is Lady Danbury?
[gasps] Your Majesty.
What evidence have you gathered?
You would like to know…
what evidence I have gathered
in my investigation of Lady Whistledown?
Are you requiring your queen
to ask again?
Oh…
Tell me what you know.
Well, I believe her a widow.
She obviously has the financial means…
-A most enjoyable party.
-Indeed.
Um, Bridgerton… Um…
The other night…
What happened the other night?
I do not believe anything happened at all.
Ah…
Very well.
Ah, dearest…
I believe you know Mr. Bridgerton.
My wife, Mrs. Lucy Granville.
It is a pleasure, Mr. Bridgerton.
Mm.
I spoke to the duke.
That makes one of us.
He refused your dowry.
Is this your attempt to raise my spirits?
He refused for your benefit, sister.
I shall put the money in trust,
so you may use it how you see fit.
For your children, perhaps.
Certainly, you two will have a brood
large enough to put Mother's to shame.
-What? Is something wrong?
-I am…
This is all…
I must take a moment. Excuse me.
[breathing heavily]
[knocking at door]
[Violet chuckles lightly]
I know it must be difficult
to be leaving this house.
I have many memories here.
And you will make new ones
with your husband.
Ah, my husband.
Seems so strange
to finally be able to say that.
I suppose I have put this conversation off
for as long as I can.
[chuckles nervously]
On my wedding day,
I insisted Cook bring out
round after round of food,
in part because I did not want
the celebration to end, but…
if I must confess,
I was also quite apprehensive…
of my wedding night.
In fact, I was quite full
by the time we got to Aubrey Hall.
I certainly do not recommend that.
Well, what do you recommend, Mama?
I know you and the duke--
Well, whatever took place
between the two of you…
You may very well
know some things already.
I know nothing, I assure you.
Well, there are some things
you ought to know.
Some things that will happen
that involve you and your husband…
The duke, obviously.
Well, he… You see…
the marital act,
which, now that you are married,
you may perform…
If it is this difficult to discuss,
how difficult must it be to perform?
It is not, dearest. It is most natural.
Much in the way
that rain soaks a field in autumn,
and in spring, flowers grow.
-[Violet grunts uncomfortably]
-[Daphne inhales]
When you were younger, do you remember,
we had two hounds in the country?
-[chuckles] Bassets, in fact.
-That is right.
Well, no one explained it to them…
but there were puppies.
I see. So…
So, this act,
it is performed to have children?
Yes! [laughs, sighs]
But…
what if the duke
and I cannot have children?
Does that prevent us
from performing this act at all,
from even having a wedding night at all?
Dear, is this your concern?
[chuckles]
Daphne, the two of you
care for each other deeply.
When all is said and done,
nothing else matters.
There is no reason to be concerned.
[chuckles]
-I still have so many questions, Mama.
-[knocking at door]
-They are bringing the carriages around.
-It is time.
[sighs]
Perhaps I can come with you.
I've always wanted to live in a castle.
If Daphne is going to take anyone
with her, Gregory, it will be me.
The two of you are staying here
until our dear sister allows us a visit.
You mean <span style="style2">if she allows us a visit.
I'm sure you'll enjoy the peace and quiet.
I am going to miss all of you terribly.
Even me?
Even you.
I have a present for you.
It is upstairs, made of four walls
and a very comfortable bed.
I suppose
the light in your room is quite pleasant.
I know we could not be any more different,
but there is one thing we do share,
the certainty that you will make
your own way in this world.
I am sure of it, Eloise.
-Write to me as soon as you arrive.
-Of course, Mama.
You are going to be a wonderful duchess.
[carriage door opens]
-[carriage door closes]
-[horse whinnies]
[sighs]
We should reach the inn before nightfall.
The inn?
Clyvedon is much too far a journey,
and the roads are not safe after dusk.
We need to rest
before continuing on in the morning.
So we will be spending
our wedding night at the inn?
Why…
I should have told you.
Not at all.
[sighs]
I do hope everything is to your liking.
Should you require anything else at all,
please let me know.
Ah, here we are.
-Your room, Your Grace, is just over here.
-[inhales sharply]
I requested a separate room.
Yes.
-Should I--
-Yes.
Yes.
[panting rapidly]
We should go down to dinner.
[sighs deeply]
Daphne? I…
Are you not hungry?
The food is excellent here, I assure you.
-The last time I visited--
-I do not want any dinner!
I have spent the last three days
wanting to be alone with you,
wanting to talk to you, wanting to know.
I understand
that you do not wish to see me,
that you would prefer to stay
in your separate room
and endure a wordless dinner together
on our wedding night, but I--
-That is not what I would prefer.
-Simon--
You are mistaken.
-You have avoided my presence.
-In order to allow you your liberty.
You have said all but a few words to me.
In order to keep myself
from saying the wrong things.
You've barely been able
to look me in the eye.
I could not bear witness
to the misery I have caused you.
You did not…
I am the one
who trapped you into this marriage.
I trapped you.
I have spent the last three days in agony…
unable to talk to you,
unable to be alone with you,
because I knew
you wanted nothing to do with me.
And understandably so, after forcing you
to make an unimaginable sacrifice.
You wanted a life with children, a family.
You wanted a life
with a man you truly knew.
You wanted a love match, and yet--
And yet…
this could not be any more different.
Is that what you hoped to say?
[exhales sharply]
I shall join you for dinner momentarily.
[sighs tremulously]
Everything I told the queen was true.
I cannot stop thinking of you.
From the mornings you ease,
to the evenings you quiet,
to the dreams you inhabit…
my thoughts of you never end.
I am yours, Daphne.
I have always been yours.
I…
I do not understand.
I do not know how to be any more clear.
-Do not get angry.
-I am not angry. I--
You look angry and bothered.
Look at you, you are downright flushed.
-Yes, that is what happens.
-When one is angry.
When one burns for someone
who does not feel the same!
[Simon sighs]
You…
burn for me?
Why do you think
I followed you into that garden?
Why do you think I went into that garden?
If you would have only
looked at me this week
for longer than two seconds,
you would have seen.
It is you I cannot sacrifice.
I burn…
for you.
[soft romantic music plays]
[both breathing passionately]
[whispering] What are you…
-Simon?
-Do you want me to stop?
No. [gasps]
Do you want me to stop?
I want to show you more.
More?
[both breathing heavily]
[Daphne breathing tremulously]
[both sighing]
Did you touch yourself…
like we talked about?
Show me.
I…
I cannot.
[quivering sigh]
[gasps]
Tell me what you thought about
when you were alone.
[gasping] I thought about…
[inhales sharply]
Simon, I need you closer.
[inhales deeply]
[gasps]
This may hurt a moment.
[Daphne gasps sharply]
[Daphne grunts, moans]
[gasps, moans]
[soft romantic music continues]
[both gasping]
I thought about you.
When I touch myself,
I always think about you.
[gasping intensifies]
[gasping crescendos]
[Daphne moans]
[both breathing heavily]
[Daphne chuckles]
How do you feel?
I feel…
[chuckles] I feel…
wonderful.
[chuckles]
[sighs]